[Music]
thank you
all righty y'all so welcome back to GM
outdoors I hope everybody's having a
fantastic day today the weather's
finally decided to take a turn for the
better here in the sun is starting to
peek through the clouds there so I
figured what a better time than to come
out here and do another product review
for y'all so
today we're going to be doing a product
review on the olathes motion security
light uh olafis is a company that has a
variety of different things to pick from
anything light decorative lights
interior exterior flood lights work
lights even party lights they've even
got some speakers on there too uh
everything in the images and things
seems to be of high quality uh but today
I've got a 5500 Lumen motion security
light supposed to have about 335 degree
broadcast of the light and I'm going to
replace this one here in between my two
garage doors that come on the house and
we bought it so it's a very old light
and this one here is all LED and should
save me 85 percent more on my electric
bill so come along with us here and
stick around we'll put this thing up
together come on
alrighty so let's go ahead and get this
box opened up here so like I said before
this is the olathes 5500 Lumen motion
security light
all right so right out the gate here you
can tell that it's packaged well
so that way it stays good and safe on
the way in
got our instructions here
got some Hardware here let's see what
else
some wire nuts
screws there
go ahead and get the get the light
itself out now
alrighty
so
right off the bat I can tell it's made
out of really nice material here and I
love how these lights are adjustable or
you can really fit it to your needs
whatever you're trying to do oh yeah
so it just flips up there
you can adjust them all the way around
all these are LED which is going to be
super bright and here's the motion
sensor which has got a 120 degree range
of motion on it to pick up
and underneath here is all the settings
so you've got the motion sensitivity
setting right here the
what time of day it will come on so uh
minus all the way minus will only work
at night and all the way plus here will
only work uh we'll work day in night
and then you've got the run time for how
long the light will actually stay on
once it picks up motion I think the
minimum is two minutes and the maximum
is seven minutes so
and of course you got your wires here in
the back your uh
flat black and ground so let's go ahead
and get this old one off the house and
put the new one up all righty so first
things first you want to make sure you
got the power cut off to the lights
you're going to be working on uh so
before you do anything to it at all make
sure you go cut the breaker off to it
because if you don't that electricity
will remind you real quick in a hurry
that you should have done it so anyhow I
done went and cut the breaker off this
particular light we're going to be
working on and uh let's go ahead and get
the old one off and get the new one put
back on
all righty well the first thing I'm
going to do here is I'm going to remove
these light bulbs out of here and like I
said this thing is old old we've lived
here about to hit this house for about
seven eight years now and I've never
even changed the bulbs in this thing so
I've been meaning to change it for a
long time just never got around to it
because it always kind of worked but I'm
very excited to put this new Olathe one
up because I know it's going to be about
15 times brighter than this one right
here is
so let me get a screwdriver and start
taking them screws out
all right get these screws out right
fast
foreign
so now if you notice how this old one is
attached to the house here it just has a
has the wires directly to it you've got
to hold this line up here like this or
you're trying to get these wires put all
up and everything hold it up there push
it all back in there and screw it in
there now I'm going to show you
something cool that olathes has done to
make this whole process a little bit
easier but first let's get these wire
nuts off of here
and go ahead and get this line off the
house
out of the way
alrighty so what olathes has done to
make that process a little bit easier is
they've sent this uh this mounting
bracket plate along with a gasket that
goes on the back of it to keep the water
from getting inside uh and so what
you'll do is you'll put this piece of
metal up on the house and run screws
through it to hold it on the house now
this will be on the house attached
already so whenever you go to put this
line up there instead of having to get
your holes lined up and uh and start
tightening everything up while you're
holding the light up there all you've
got to do is uh
you'll have your your wires run through
this bracket like so
and uh like I said this will already be
on the house so you'll have that up
there and you just put that up there and
then while you're holding this up
all you have to deal with is one bolt
you'll just put that bolt right there in
the middle of that lock and tighten it
up and that's what holds the light onto
the house uh much much simpler than
having to hold the weight of the light
up there and uh getting all the holes
lined up and everything and screwing it
to it uh it's just a whole lot simpler
to have the bracket already on the house
and you literally just put the light on
the bracket and you've got one supplied
bolt that goes right through there to
hold it on there so let's go ahead and
get the bracket up there
and get this new light put up
all righty so I'm going to go ahead and
attach the pad that comes with this I'm
just going to peel off the center
like that
I'm going to apply it directly to the
back side
of that Circle bracket there just like
that
and I will cut out a little hole here to
put my wires through
that should be perfect
alrighty so I went ahead and cut the
hole out here for the wires to stick
through like that right there
um now olafas provides you with bolts
and things that are good to mount this
bracket directly to a junction box but
however in my situation I'm just going
to be drilling directly into the house
so I'm just going to be using the my
drill and some of these Power Pro uh two
and a half inch screws because that's
works for my particular situation so
that's what we're going to do now
so just run those wires through there
like that right there
go ahead and get your screw here
I'm going to be using two different
screws
and that should hold it in place
already
so the first thing we're going to do is
we're going to go ahead and attach our
ground wire here to the uh the grounding
screw on the mounting bracket
foreign
like that
and tighten it up there
and then I'll go ahead and hook the
black uh the Live Wire black to the
black live wire on the house and the
neutral white wire to the neutral white
wire on the house pretty straightforward
process there
foreign
like to take these connections
I always like to tape them that way
there's never a chance that they can
come in contact with each other and
maybe try to ground out or jump a spark
or something like that so tape is just
extra precaution
okay
foreign
together and taped together real good
and the ground's on there real good you
can go ahead and tuck them all
back into this hole here that you cut
out
of the bracket earlier
get them all back in there like so
and here's the part I was talking about
where you just have that one bolt to put
in there
and put that adjusted up and out of the
way where I got access to this bolt here
tightening it up
all righty
and you can adjust it down
to wherever you want it to be at which
I'll probably have it right there
and just tighten
go ahead and tighten up the adjustment
screw back here in the back
Bend these outside
in your sensor
sensor
and like I said there's three
adjustments on the bottom here too uh
once again it's the uh the sensitivity
of the motion uh and what time of day it
comes on you can have it run to where
it's only on at night or it's on both
night and day
uh and then the length of time it's all
once it's triggered so like I said the
minimum is two the high is seven minutes
uh so I'm going to have it toward only
uh comes on at night
so I'll twist that all the way over to
the minus side there
and I'll put the sensitivity to about
about three quarters of the way
maybe half we'll see
then I want it to run for probably about
five minutes or so
I'll put it about halfway
then here comes the satisfying part
filling these
oh yeah filling these stickers off
listen to it
I love doing that
all right
let's go ahead and cut the power back on
and see if we can't take a look at it
here during the daylight okay so before
I cut the power onto it here I just
really wanted to take a minute and show
you how nice of a product this is uh
very clean slim line uh
just all around made really nice very
sturdy and uh the lights hold their
position very well basically wherever
whichever way you turn them and
something that I didn't mention before
was that on the back side of the lights
uh are these cooling fans that keep it
cool uh a lot of them don't have that or
they only have a couple of them this
one's got them all the way across
because LED lights do get hot and these
coolant fins allow a lot
a lot more of uh uh cooling action on
the back for when the wind blows and to
dissipate the heat so uh like I said
it's a really nice product
all right so I'm gonna go ahead and cut
it on and see how bright it is in
daytime here
man oh man that thing is bright I can't
believe it's that right during the
daylight
so let's uh hang around here and wait
till night time comes and we'll see how
bright it is then I guarantee it'll
probably light up the whole front yard
all righty so the Sun finally went down
on us here been a couple hours later so
I'm gonna walk out here in front of this
motion line here and see if it kicks on
for me
wow
man oh man that thing is bright
I can't believe how bright that is look
at this you can see the whole front yard
wow
I mean look at that you can see all the
way down the road
the whole front yard
man oh man
what a great product
super super bright step back and look at
it
man oh man
that's really something there
wow
what a bright bright light
I just can't get over how bright that is
man I tell you can't hardly look at it
it's that bright I was I am very very
much impressed with this olathes uh
motion security light 5500 aluminum edge
is just super super bright I was not
expecting this this has lit up the
entire front yard you know that's insane
uh hope this video has done this without
Justice I am thoroughly impressed with
it it has my approval I highly recommend
this product I will definitely be
leaving a link for it in the description
below
like I said this is the olathes 5500
Lumen motion security
flood light uh just extremely bright you
can't even look at it uh I just can't
get over how bright that is it's insane
but I sure do appreciate y'all watching
this video I hope hope uh if you're in
the market for a floodlight or a motion
a lot check your slide out you will not
be disappointed for sure like I said
I'll leave a link for it in the
description and I appreciate y'all
watching and I will see you on the next
one thank y'all
foreign
[Music]